<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>webdev on Artem&#39;s Digital Garden</title>
    <link>https://aakatev.github.io/blog/tags/webdev/</link>
    <description>Recent content in webdev on Artem&#39;s Digital Garden</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2020 10:42:08 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://aakatev.github.io/blog/tags/webdev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Add a Video to Your Hugo Website</title>
      <link>https://aakatev.github.io/blog/posts/add-a-video-to-your-hugo-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2020 10:42:08 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aakatev.github.io/blog/posts/add-a-video-to-your-hugo-website/</guid>
      <description>Hugo is the world’s fastest framework for building websites. It is easy to get started, and has a fair number of customization available out of the box. It is a great choice for content creators who don&amp;rsquo;t want to spend a lot of time on HTML and CSS, but would rather focus on delivering their product to the audience.
Video is one of the most common forms of the media content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTTPS on Localhost for Any Web Application</title>
      <link>https://aakatev.github.io/blog/posts/https-on-localhost-for-any-web-application/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 10:42:08 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aakatev.github.io/blog/posts/https-on-localhost-for-any-web-application/</guid>
      <description>Having a TLS certificate is not a common requirement for local development. Moreover, many tools, like Angular or Parcel allow you to seamlessly generate certs with a runtime options. That said, sometimes you might need to serve HTTPS traffic to an application that doesn&amp;rsquo;t support TLS certificates auto-generation. In this cases, there is no elegant workaround, rather than actually generate the certificates manually. It can be done using tools, like openssl, and there is a number of great how-to articles on the topic, for example this one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Static Website Infrastructure with Terraform</title>
      <link>https://aakatev.github.io/blog/posts/terraform-static-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 10:42:08 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aakatev.github.io/blog/posts/terraform-static-website/</guid>
      <description>Deploying a static website is one of the easiest task a web developer faces. There is a number of solutions allowing to complete the deployment process in a matter of few minutes, and several buttons clicks. What a wonderful world we live in! However, this approach has one huge limitation. You don&amp;rsquo;t really own the underlying infrastructure. I claim that there is a way you can both do the deployment fast, and own the underlying infrastructure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Security 101</title>
      <link>https://aakatev.github.io/blog/posts/web-security-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 10:42:08 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aakatev.github.io/blog/posts/web-security-101/</guid>
      <description>The current document was born as part of my personal research on topic of security related to Software (SW), and specifically Web Applications. It is by no means comprehensive, but can be a good place to start getting familiar with the most common threats developers face on the World Wide Web (WWW). Each section aims to introduce a problem, or a technology. Briefly give to a reader an overview of the issue, and provide references for the further research.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
