<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tutorial on Artem&#39;s Digital Garden</title>
    <link>/tags/tutorial/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tutorial on Artem&#39;s Digital Garden</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2020 10:42:08 -1500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/tutorial/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>[Learn Hugo] Project Structure</title>
      <link>/posts/learn-hugo/project-structure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2020 10:42:08 -1500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/learn-hugo/project-structure/</guid>
      <description>Last time we talked about the difference between static and dynamic websites, and created a Hello World project using the Hugo CLI. This post will cover the project&amp;rsquo;s folder structure in more details.
Here is our hello-world project:
├── archetypes │ └── default.md ├── config.toml ├── content ├── data ├── layouts │ └── index.html ├── resources │ └── _gen │ ├── assets │ └── images ├── static └── themes First of all, you have probably noticed that running the hugo server command created resources folder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Learn Hugo] Getting Started with Static Websites</title>
      <link>/posts/learn-hugo/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2020 10:42:08 -0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/learn-hugo/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>I have published a number of posts featuring Hugo. They got the least number of views and responses I have ever had on dev.to. Considering this fact, I don&amp;rsquo;t know why I decided it would be a good idea to have the whole series of articles dedicated to &amp;ldquo;the world’s fastest framework for building websites&amp;rdquo;.
The format for the series is going to be beginner friendly. Each post covers a single feature, or some subset of a feature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BigBlueButton JS</title>
      <link>/projects/bigbluebutton-js/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2020 10:42:08 -0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/bigbluebutton-js/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Add a Video to Your Hugo Website</title>
      <link>/posts/add-a-video-to-your-hugo-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2020 10:42:08 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/add-a-video-to-your-hugo-website/</guid>
      <description>Hugo is the world’s fastest framework for building websites. It is easy to get started, and has a fair number of customization available out of the box. It is a great choice for content creators who don&amp;rsquo;t want to spend a lot of time on HTML and CSS, but would rather focus on delivering their product to the audience.
Video is one of the most common forms of the media content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three JS Webpack Boilerplate</title>
      <link>/projects/three-js-webpack/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 10:42:08 -0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/three-js-webpack/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTTPS on Localhost for Any Web Application</title>
      <link>/posts/https-on-localhost-for-any-web-application/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 10:42:08 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/https-on-localhost-for-any-web-application/</guid>
      <description>Having a TLS certificate is not a common requirement for local development. Moreover, many tools, like Angular or Parcel allow you to seamlessly generate certs with a runtime options. That said, sometimes you might need to serve HTTPS traffic to an application that doesn&amp;rsquo;t support TLS certificates auto-generation. In this cases, there is no elegant workaround, rather than actually generate the certificates manually. It can be done using tools, like openssl, and there is a number of great how-to articles on the topic, for example this one.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
